JESSE MORGUTIA

Cell: 626-383-3394 Email: jvmorgutia@gmail.com Website: jvmorgutia.github.io

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with excellent communication skills and a strong foundation in software development; experienced across various platforms with success in working both independently, and in a team environment. A fast and dedicated learner interested in a challenging career as a software developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & ABILITIES

- Languages: C#, Java, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, XAML, XML, JSON
- Software/Tools: Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Eclipse, Android Studio, Xcode, Photoshop, Illustrator
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, OSX

EDUCATION

California State Polytechnic University

Pomona, CA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Sept 2010 - June 2015

• Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Systems, Computer Networks, Cloud Computing, Computer Graphics, Discrete Structures, Graphical User Interfaces

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- JNotepad: An enhanced clone of Microsoft's Notepad with additional features and syntax highlighting for several programming languages. Compatible with OSX, Linux, and Windows. Written in Java (using Swing). *Individual project*
- **CosmosKernel**: A command-line based operating system kernel, with basic functions, batch functionality (sequential processing implementation), and a file system. Written in C#. *Group project, role: Developer*
- AlarmCast: An Android application that streams media content to a connected Chromecast (TV) when a device's
 alarm goes off. Written in Java (using Android Studio). Group Project, role: Developer(UI)

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II

CU Direct

January 2017 to Present

Responsible for enhancing and developing towards several CU Direct Lending platforms.. My most recent projects
focus on third party service integration and full stack development.

Software Developer I

CU Direct

July 2015 to December 2016

Responsibilities are focused toward maintaining and developing features for CU Direct's Lending software. My most
recent work projects include web service integration, back end development, and UI development using Visual Studio
(C#, WPF using MVVM, XAML, SQL, JSON, XML).

Software Development Intern

CU Direct

Feb 2015 to July 2015

- Responsible for contributing towards the development of several web/mobile applications using ASP.NET MVC development in Visual Studio (C#, Razor, JavaScript, CSS, and MS SQL Server).
- Engaged in a daily scrum with software designers, developers, and QA engineers in order to review outstanding issues and improve project quality prior to, during and after development.

Quality Assurance Intern

CU Direct

July 2014 to June 2015

- Awarded Team of the Quarter (Q3 2014) for contributing to the success of AutoSMART 3.0.
- Responsible for verification of application functionality, test planning, regression testing, data validation, and documentation of defects.
- Maintained consistent collaboration with software designers and developers in attempts to meet requirements and review current issues prior to, and during test case execution.

Lead Apple Certified Macintosh Technician

Cal Poly Pomona Foundation - Bronco Bookstore

Sept 2012 to July 2014

- Increased customer satisfaction rates for three consecutive quarters (based on Apple GSX reporting).
- Diagnosed, documented and repaired computer hardware, software, and networking issues.
- Created graphic media(flyers, logos, etc.) and updated/maintained website information; BroncoBookstore.com
- Managed multiple servers (data reporting and file sharing)
- Trained new employees and assisted customers with technical questions.